Speaker: Schools all over the country are encouraging students to study STEM subjects
– that is, science, technology, engineering, and mathematics
– as these are what businesses consider to be the most important areas of study
for our workforces of the future.
The pie charts you can see here show the changes in the percentage of students
taking A levels in STEM subjects at Dashwood Secondary School over a five-year period,
from 2020 to 2025.
The most popular subject in 2020 was economics, which was studied by 28.5% of students.
In 2025, the percentage increased slightly, by 2%, to 30.5%.
By the end of the period, however,
economics was replaced as the most popular subject by computer science,
where the percentage rose from 20.5 to 35.6% over the five years.
The least popular subject in 2020 was physics, at just 5.1%.
By 2025, its popularity decreased even further, by 0.3%, to 4.8%.
Physics was one of the two STEM subjects where numbers actually dropped.
The other was maths, which was studied by 26.4% of students in 2020, but only 7.4% in 2025,
a decrease of nearly three quarters.
As regards the other two STEM subjects, in 2020, chemistry was more popular than physics,
at 11.1%, rising slightly to 12.2% in 2025.
Biology also rose in popularity, from 8.4 to 9.5%.
Overall, the results are encouraging.
The government is monitoring the changes
and hoping that the overall take-up of all STEM subjects will gradually increase.